<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
  ~ Copyright (c) 2007-2018 AREasy Runtime
  ~
  ~ This library, AREasy Runtime and API for BMC Remedy AR System, is free software ("Licensed Software");
  ~ you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
  ~ License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2.1 of the License,
  ~ or (at your option) any later version.
  ~
  ~ This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY;
  ~ including but not limited to, the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY, NONINFRINGEMENT,
  ~ or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.
  -->

<help inherits="data/base.data.xml">
	<name>Remove Support Group Membership</name>
	<description><![CDATA[
This action is an ITSM utility, designed to remove support group membership for one or many people accounts.

The standard command line is described below:
areasy -action admin.set.sgroup.member [-login <val>] [-logins <val1> <val2> ... <valn>] [-fieldid <CTM:People field id> [-fieldvalue <CTM:People field value>]] [-sgroupcompany <current support group company>] [-sgrouporganisation <current support group organisation>] [-sgroupname <current support group name>] [-sgroupid <support group id>] [-findusers] [-findgroups]


Where:
	-sgroupcompany      = support group company. In addition the action supports another alias for this option: -supportgroupcompany. This option is used to identify the support group entity

	-sgrouporganisation = support group organisation. In addition the action supports another alias for this option: -supportgrouporganisation. This option is used to identify the support group entity

	-sgroupname         = support group name. In addition the action supports some aliases for these options: -sgroup, -supportgroup, -supportgroupname. This option is used to identify the support group entity

	-sgroupid           = support group id. Also this option has an alias and this is -supportgroupid. So, first four options have to be used to identify the support group entity

	-login              = Remedy user id

	-logins             = list of Remedy user ids

	-userfieldid        = a specific field Id from CTM:People form (or other form in case of 'userformname' option is specified) to the create a qualification criteria to identify the login ids where this permission have to the applied

	-userfieldvalue     = the corresponding value for -fieldid option to compose the qualification criteria: <CTM:People fieldid> = <fieldvalue>. From the found people records will be extracted login ids that will be appended to the specified list through -login(s) option

	-userqualifiation   = this could be the third option to take the list of persons and to provide them additional roles. Actually this option provide a way to select persons using a qualification criteria addressed to the direct connected AR System server.

	-userformname       = in case of 'userqualifiation' is used you can say a value for this option to find the usernames into an independent Remedy form (also you have to use 'userfieldid' to specify the field id that will be read from that form) or don't specify it and will search directly in People form and will read 'Remedy Login ID' field

	-findusers          = in case of support group is specified and no other people account is mentioned in the command line this option will allows to discover all users that currently are members of the specified group and the action will remove the membership for these users

Examples:
---------
1) areasy -runtime -action admin.remove.sgroup.member -supportgroupcompany "Calbro Services" -supportgrouporganisation "Services Performance" -supportgroupname "Development" -login appadmin
	= remove appadmin from support group "Calbro Services">Services Performance">"Development"

2) areasy -runtime -action admin.remove.sgroup.member -supportgroupcompany "Calbro Services" -supportgrouporganisation "Services Performance" -supportgroupname "Development"  -findusers
	= remove all users from support group "Calbro Services">Services Performance">"Development"

3) areasy -runtime -action admin.remove.sgroup.member -logins appadmin john -findgroups
	= remove all support group memberships for users appadmin and john
	]]></description>
	<syntax>
		areasy -action admin.set.sgroup.member
	</syntax>
	<samples>
		<sample code="" description=""/>
	</samples>
</help>