Status
======

Status action displays the environment details of the runtime instance or displays the current status of the AREasy server instance including details about runtime server execution channels.

The standard command line is described below:
areasy -action status [-environment] [-channels [<true|channel id(s)>]] [-channel <channel name or number>] [-call <action name> [-signal]] [-repeat <val1> [-sleep <milliseconds>]]

Where:
	-environment = displays environment details about the runtime instance. If the action runs in client/server mode, the option will display also the figures about server execution channels. This option is default selected when the action is called without any switch. The option is skipped in case of is not specified explicitly and -channel(s) option is asked.

	-channels    = if the option doesn't have value(s) it will display the list of execution channels, the actions that run on each channel and their status. In case of the option is asked with a value or a list of values it will return the real-time status message delivered by each action under execution.

	-channel     = displays the status message for the action that runs on the specified channel number.

	-call        = displays the status messages delivered by all channels that runs the specified action name

	-signal      = returns bit 0 instead of read status message (that will become a log message). This option works together with -call or -channel(s)

	-sleep       = after execution the action will wait the specified number of milliseconds till will return the control to the runtime management. This behaviour is applicable only if the action is running in client/server mode.

	-repeat      = this option works only if -sleep has a value greater than 0 and when -call or -channel(s) options are included in the status interrogation. This option will repeat interrogation of channels list according to the specified repetition number and if this value is 0 the status message will loop continuously till no signal is found on all execution channels.


Examples:
---------
1) areasy -action status
	= displays environment details

2) areasy -action status -channels
	= displays channels execution list

3) areasy -action status -environment -channels
	= displays environment details and channels execution list

4) areasy -action status -channels 3 5
	= displays the status messages for channels 2 and 3

5) areasy -action status -channel 2
	= displays the status message for channel 2

6) areasy -action status -call "data.wrapper.file"
	= displays the status messages for all channels where 'data.wrapper.file' runs

7) areasy -action status -channels 3 5 -sleep 3000 -repeat 5
	= displays the status messages for channels 3 and 5 and repeat the interrogation 5 times, from 3 to 3 seconds

8) areasy -action status -call "data.wrapper.file" -sleep 5000 -repeat 0
	= displays the status messages for all channels where 'data.wrapper.file' runs and repeat the interrogation from 5 to 5 seconds will no one of these channels will have signal